teachingamericanhistory.org 2019-11-26

# Privacy Policy - Teaching American History

Your privacy is important to us. 

When you place an order or request information from TeachingAmericanHistory.org, be assured that we do not share, sell, trade, or otherwise disclose any of our customer information at any time.  
  
Our customer database will not be sold or rented to other companies for mailing-list or mass-email distribution purposes. The information you provide on this website will be maintained in the strictest confidentiality at all times.  
  
We collect three basic types of information from you in conjunction with your use of the site: (1) personal information, (e.g., your name, shipping and billing addresses, email address, telephone number), (2) non-personal information, (e.g., purchase information), and (3) device information, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. This information comes to us from Google Analytics tracking data, and is not explicitly linked to your use of the site.  
  
We may ask you to provide your personal information when you register for an account, make a purchase, or sign up to receive email newsletters via Pardot for Salesforce.  
  
We use the order information that we collect to fulfill orders placed through the site. Payment information is processed via a 3rd-party service, Linvio. We do not store any payment information in our database. Our checkout form sends payment information directly to Linvio’s servers, without storing that data in our server. After a successful charge, Linvio sends us an anonymous token, which we store, that uniquely identifies each transaction.  
  
Order fulfillment and shipping is handled by our on-location warehouse. Our customer service representatives may use personal information you provide to provide you with invoices and/or order inquiries or confirmations.  
  
We note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (e.g., placing an order), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above.  
  
When you place an order through the site, we will maintain your order information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information. Users can delete their own account information by editing their profiles and clicking “Cancel my account.”  
  
You have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. Users can download user information and purchase history as a machine-readable file in their profile by clicking “Export my data.”  
  
We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the site. Data retention for our analytics accounts are set to retain information for tracking historical data.  
  
We may also share your personal information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.  
  
We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal, or regulatory reasons.  
  
If you have questions about this privacy policy, please contact us by email at [info@teachingamericanhistory.org](mailto:info@teachingamericanhistory.org).
